Katherine Salesin

Ph.D. Student, Dartmouth College







PHanover, NH — cs.dartmouth.edu/~ksalesin / katherine.a.salesin.gr@dartmouth.edu

Research Interests



My current research is on the fusion of physically based rendering in computer graphics with radiative transfer problems in other scientific fields such as oceanography, atmospheric science, and astronomy. I find projects that encourage going outside and exploring the real world particularly exciting.

Education
Ph.D., Dartmouth College Sept. 2018 – present Computer Science
Advisor: Wojciech Jarosz
B.S. with Distinction, Cornell University Computer Science, Minor: Marine Biology Dean's List (5/8 semesters) Advisor: Kavita Bala
Awards, Grants, & Fellowships
Future Investigators in NASA Earth and Space Science and Technology Grant
NASA Grant
2nd Place, Poster Session (Computer Science Category)
Patrick Tsang Memorial Best TA Award
Runner Up, Rendering Competition

Publications



Unifying radiative transfer models in computer graphics and remote sensing, Part I: A survey. Katherine Salesin, Kirk D. Knobelspiesse, Jacek Chowdhary, Peng-Wang Zhai, Wojciech Jarosz. Journal of Quantitative Spectroscopy and Radiative Transfer, 314, February 2024.

Unifying radiative transfer models in computer graphics and remote sensing, Part II: A differentiable, polarimetric forward model and validation. Katherine Salesin, Kirk D. Knobelspiesse, Jacek Chowdhary, Peng-Wang Zhai, Wojciech Jarosz. Journal of Quantitative Spectroscopy and Radiative Transfer, 315, March 2024.

DIY hyperspectral imaging via polarization-induced spectral filters. <u>Katherine Salesin</u>, Dario Seyb, Sarah Friday, Wojciech Jarosz. 2022 IEEE International Conference on Computational Photography (ICCP). pp. 1-12. August 2022.

Combining Point and Line Samples for Direct Illumination. <u>Katherine Salesin</u>, Wojciech Jarosz. Computer Graphics Forum (Proceedings of EGSR), 38(4), July 2019.

Presentations



DIY hyperspectral imaging via polarization-induced spectral filters. <u>Katherine Salesin</u>, Dario Seyb, Sarah Friday, Wojciech Jarosz. 2022 IEEE International Conference on Computational Photography (ICCP). Pasadena, CA (Virtual). August 2022.

Forward and inverse polarized light rendering with Mitsuba 2. Ocean Ecology Laboratory Seminar. NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (Virtual). August 2021.

Combining Point and Line Samples for Direct Illumination. Eurographics Symposium on Rendering. Strasbourg, France. July 2019.

Research Experience



I supported the upcoming PACE satellite mission by extending the new research renderer Mitsuba 2 to perform hyperrealistic, polarized simulations of interest to the remote sensing community.

Photonic Sentry is a Global Good/Intellectual Ventures start-up that has created a laser that zaps mosquitoes, psyllids, and other pests out of the air. I created tools for logging, organizing, and visualizing live research data from lasers and cameras. Data typically included system statuses, bug stats, and bug flight paths.

I assisted Prof. Steve Marschner on a project to create a realistic wood texture authoring tool. I prepared wood samples and measured their reflective properties using a spherical gantry.

Teaching Experience



I designed and ran the graduate reading course for Master's in Digital Arts students, which included writing the syllabus and assignments, running discussions, and arranging presentations by guest speakers.

CS 10: Problem Solving via Object-Oriented Programming CS 98: Senior Design and Implementation Project
Station Leader
Science Day at Dartmouth is an annual event where graduate students teach kids about their research through fun, hands-on activities. I designed a computer graphics station that taught kids some of the science behind their favorite movies and video games, and we acted out ray tracing in real life!
Deckhand/Educator
I sailed on schooner Seaward on San Francisco Bay and along the California coast with students grade 3-12. I created interactive lesson plans and taught basic marine biology, ecology, modern and historical navigation, scientific data collection, and seamanship.
Sailing Intern
I sailed on SSV Robert C. Seamans in the South Pacific near New Zealand as part of SEA Semester's Ocean Exploration program. I taught college students the fundamentals of sailing, seamanship, celestial and modern navigation, and oceanographic research on a tall ship.
Teaching Assistant
CS 4620: Introduction to Computer Graphics CS 5625: Interactive Computer Graphics
Mentor Experience
Faria Huq
Hsu (Carter) Cheng 2020 – 2021 Master's Thesis
Service & Professional Activities
Executive Committee Member
Spotlight Coordinator
WiGRAPH (Women in Computer Graphics Research)
WiGRAPH (Women in Computer Graphics Research) Member
WiGRAPH (Women in Computer Graphics Research) Member
WiGRAPH (Women in Computer Graphics Research) Member

Dartmouth Spring Hackathon

Station Leader	2019, 2022
Member	2015 – 2016

Selected Classes



These are some of the classes I have taken at a graduate level during my PhD.

Computer Graphics • Rendering Algorithms • Computational Photography • Machine Learning & Statistical Analysis • Deep Learning • Physical Computing • GPU Programming and High-Performance Computing